Finding Aid for the Arai Family Papers LSC.1254
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Files (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 
  - Arai Ryichir. (Box 55)
    - Drafts of letters. (Box 55)
    - Travel, 1910. (Box 55)
      - Passenger list for TKK SS Shinyo Maru, Yokohama to San Francisco via Honolulu, September 21, 1912.; (5 × 4 folded).
      - Bill from Grands Magisins du Louvre, 1910.; (4 × 8).
      - Bill from Hotel des Champs Elysees (2)., (9 × 12).
    - Golf. (Box 55)
    - Personal financial papers, 1893-1909. (Box 55)
    - Holy Cross Gold Mining & Mining Co. (Box 55)
      - 3 stock certificates for Ryichir Arai, 1896-97.; (8 × 11).
    - Bank statements, 1935-36. (Box 55)
    - Morimura & Co. (Morimura Bank) statements, 1885-1914. (Box 55)
    - Memo: financial statement., 1904-05 (Box 55)
      - * Memo book from Higeta Soy (Shoyu Brewery)., (3 × 4).
    - Memorabilia. (Box 55)
      - Guest list of reception for Emperor's birthday at the Plaza (New York) by Consul General and Madame K Midzuno, November 3, 1910.; (11 × 15).
      - * Kobe Golf Club score card (blank)., (2 × 5 folded).
      - Bill from Hotel d'Europe S.A. St. Petersbourg., (8 × 15).
    - Commendation, 1924. (Box 55)
  - Correspondence relating to Miyo Arai's engagement. (Box 56)
  - Arai Yoneo decoration, 1968. (Box 56)
  - Personal papers. (Box 56)
  - Documents relating to the land in Hayama. (Box 56)
  - Arai residence plan in Tokyo. (Box 56)
  - Correspondence re Hoshino family & their lands, 1898-1912. (Box 56)
  - Powers of Attorney. (Box 56)
    - Yoneo Arai appointed Ryichir Arai his attorney, April 27, 1923.
    - Tadzu Arai appointed Yoneo Arai his attorney while at United States Consul in Yokohama, March 26, 1921.
  - Documents relating to the holding and management of the lands possessed by the Arai Family (Box 56)
  - IOU's Hoshino, 1898-1912. (Box 56)
  - Documents relating to the lands belonging to the Hoshino family, 1890-1910. (Box 56)
  - Financial records. (Box 56)
  - Riverside Property Testaments (Putnam Trust Company). (Box 56)
    - Mortgage Deed,, Yoneo Arai in Greenwich, Connecticut, March 3, 1922; (8 × 17, 4pp.).
    - Promissory Note, for 50,000 yen to Yokohama Specie Bank signed by T. Ushiba, Yoneo Arai's attorney, April 10, 1930; (3 × 9).
  - Insurance. (Box 56)
  - Sample skein of raw silk, 1877. (Box 57)
  - Doshin Kaisha. (Box 57)
    - Agreement.
    - Dissolution of partnership, (Takaki Co.), 1894
    - Correspondence, Arai to Takaki, 1886.
    - Correspondence, Morimura Toyo, 1885
    - Miscellaneous statements.
  - Morimura, Arai & Co. (Box 57)
    - Correspondence, Knevals E. Perry (Attorney at Law), 1898-1900. (Box 57)
    - Partnership agreement, October 1893 & November 1894. (Box 57)
      - Between Yaskata Murai, Richard Von Briessen and Ryichir Arai under firm name Morimura, Arai & Co., (8 × 14, 4pp.).
      - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. Charter, 1915.; (8 × 14, 6pp. typed).
    - Financial reports, 1916. (Box 57)
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. and Morimura, Arai & Co., 1883-1935. (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous, financial records & statements.
    - Arai Ryichir financial Deeds.
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. (Box 57)
    - Partners, 1898-1912.
    - Charter, 1915.
    - Partnership agreement, 1900-15.
    - Powers of Attorney, 1894-1912.
    - Partnership agreement, November 1894
    - Agreement loan: Arai Ryichir, 1897.
    - Agreement: re bank loan, 1904.
  - Nippon Ki-ito Kaisha Ltd. agreements. (Box 57)
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. (Box 57)
    - Agreement (copies). (Box 57)
    - Agreement, draft, 1904 (Box 57)
    - Dissolution, 1925. (Box 57)
    - Correspondence. (Box 57)
      - ca. 1900-17.
      - Arakawa, 1907-09.
      - Sato, 1900-18.
    - According records, 1917-18. (Box 57)
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. various reports. (Box 58)
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. circulars (Box 58)
    - Loans from Morimura Bank, 1904. (Box 58)
    - Establishment, 1915. (Box 58)
    - List of employees, 1917. (Box 58)
    - Rules and Regulations, 1915 & 1924. (Box 58)
    - Special Report, March 20, 1920. (Box 58)
    - Agreement on the Sale of the Dale Mill, Peterson, New Jersey, February 1894. (Box 58)
    - Report on Earthquake Damages, 1923. (Box 58)
    - Correspondence regarding Liquidation. (Box 58)
    - Liquidation. (Box 58)
      - Machine Department.
      - Cotton Department.
    - Correspondence. (Box 58)
      - Liquidation - Ushiba Tetsuro, 1934-35.
      - Hofman, 1935.
    - Various financial reports, 1923 & 1924. (Box 58)
  - Arai's personal memos. (Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 58)
  - Damaged documents. (Box 58)
  - Financial report. (Box 58)
  - Yokohama Ki-ito Kaisha, Ltd. (Box 59)
    - Liquidation Reports (II), January 22, 1930-January 16, 1939.
    - Documents relating to Liquidation meeting, 1933-38.
    - Liquidation Reports (I), August 23, 1924-November 25, 1929.
  - Bulletins of the Garden Club of America, 1940s-1960s. (Box 60, Box 61)
  - Books. (Box 62, Box 63, Box 64)
  - Photographs (more detailed item description in Photographs section). (Box 65, Box 66, Box 67, Box 68)
  - Books. (Box 69)
- Photographs (Box [45-47], Box [65-68])
  - Photographs, (1939).; (2 albums & 1 folder). (Box 45)
    - Black Album: Photos of home and surroundings, family, friends, Mrs. Arai in Riverside, Connecticut (on the Chichiba-Maru mixed passengers and crew photos.), 1915, 1924, 1927, 1929, 1930, 1935, 1936. 1955
    - Brown Album: Men and women in Japan and the United States., (small 3 × 4 portraits).
    - Two dinner programs. Annual dinner of The North Carolina Society of New York, honoring newly elected President Taft. Program included five speeches, including Bringing Immigrants to the South and The Negro and His Training, December 7, 1908; (on 8 × 11 heavy stock).
  - Photographs., (7 folders). (Box 46)
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - Family portraits. (Box 46)
        - Mr. & Mrs. Ichizaemon Morimura, August 1910.; (3 × 5 in cardboard frame).
        - Wedding photo Mr. & Mrs. Toshiyuki Morimura., (7 × 9).
        - Mr. & Mrs. I Morimura, Mr. & Mrs. Kaisaku and Umeko Morimura and child Matsuko., (8 × 5).
        - Morimura family in front of home, names on back, August 1910.; (4 × 6).
      - Individual portraits. (Box 46)
        - Ryichir Arai, 1906.; (3 × 5).
        - S(?) Arakawa, 1908.; (5 × 7).
        - Antoinette Butler, child, 1895.; (4 × 7).
        - Kaisaku Morimura, December 1900.; (3 × 5).
      - Group photo, Four boys Huore Takeo, Okura Kazuchika, Morimura Kaisaku, Huore Sanemichi, December 1899.; (3 × 6). (Box 46)
      - Ribbon Testimonial to Colonel Frank W. Cheney, October 25, 1899; (4 × 8). (Box 46)
      - Kaisabu Morimura, December 1900.; (3 × 5). (Box 46)
      - Page from New York Times, article Saito Says Japan's People Insist on 'Eventual Party', November 4, 1934 (Box 46)
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - Boy Scout Troop(?) with one Japanese American boy in group., (6 × 8).
      - Portraits of unidentified men, 1909.
      - Japanese American women with Japanese caption, October 1905.; (3 × 5).
      - Two women, three men by Niagara River, c1900.; (7 × 8).
      - Toyo, Katherine(?) Murai age 10 mos, c1900.; (3 × 5).
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - Richard Von Briessen, undated; (3 × 5).
      - Snapshots and family photos.
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - Individual poses in Paris, captions in Japanese, 1880s; (3 × 2).
      - Kimi Morimura, 100 days old, January 1893.
      - S Ohiashe(?), August 22, 1894.
      - Dr. Jukichi Takamine & Dr. Aoyama, March 1904.; (2 × 4).
      - Individual 3 × 2 poses. (Box 46)
        - S. Takaki in Paris.
        - T. Isikawa as a boy.
        - I. Mishima, New York, December 4, 1888.
        - A. Toruinaga, Berlin, Hamburg, March 9, 1888
        - I. Yamanouchi, c1890.
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - B.H.A. Hofmann oval, 1906.; (3 × 4).
      - Frances Keyo Tetsuka, January 1, 1903.; (3 × 5).
      - Hisako Matsukata., (5 × 7).
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - N. Sato, New York, July 16, 1904.; (3 × 5).
      - Wataro Hoshino, c1900.
      - Ichitaro Morimura and friend, 1881.; (3 × 5).
      - Kiyo sister of Shigeo, May 1906.
    - Folder. (Box 46)
      - K. Morimura, May 1895.
      - Shoji Otake, c1890.; (3 × 5).
      - Nakashima, 1875.; (2 × 3).
      - M. Morimura, November 26, 1896.; (3 × 5).
  - Photographs - Arai (1900) Murai, Morimura, Ryichir Arai., (9 folders). (Box 47)
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Portrait of children, Girl Miyo born boy Yone looks 2 yrs. older than Miyo, Ushiba grandma (Michi), Yone (6 mos), Tetsuro Ushiba, Tazu Arai, August 26, 1889 (?); 4 × 6.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Japan picture of family, 1917
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Mrs. Arai's portraits - single and with her family (Ushiba).
      - Baby Ryozo Arai born, June 11, 1920.
      - Emi Arai, 1919.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - All: Yone Arai (born August 26, 1889) growing years, 1890, 1900 & 1912.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Ryichir Arai (grandfather) portraits, 1877, 1885, 1892, 1899 & 1905.
      - One of four businessmen and Miyo, Yone, and Ryichir, 1900s.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Odds and ends family, Mrs. Arai, children, non-Japanese.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Morimura bros (?-3), October 1895.
      - Early Nisei Jay Takaki, 3 1/2 yrs. old, June 5, 1886.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - * Unusual photo: Father and daughter in affectionate pose, 1880s.
      - Mixture of 2 × 4 & 4 × 6 early photos.
    - Folder. (Box 47)
      - Miyo Arai, 2 portraits kimono sitting, gown sitting, 1909.
      - Niizuno children, Yukio, Sato (boy), Junie (girl), 1911.
  - Photographs., Plastic covered larger portraits: (Box 65)
    - Theater staged shots Early association of Japanese, with 1 caucasian, ca. 1890.; (12 × 14).
    - Young girl portrait (?), ca. 1819
    - Dinner Baron Sakatani and Mr. Majoshi, May 22, 1908.
    - Japanese military (2). General's portrait.
    - Emperor Hirohito's enthronement celebration by Japanese residents of New York and vicinity, Hotel Astor, November 16, 1928.
    - Portrait of man, large (Arai?).
  - Photographs. (Box 66)
    - Panoramic photos. (Box 66)
      - * Japan in and early life in the United States. Family house and surroundings. Tennis, ping pong, go games with family members., 1870s-80s
      - * Arai and Murai houses, panoramic shots with tennis court in foreground.
      - * Interesting home environment in panoramic album.
    - Japanese Ikebana album, 1938.; (hardbound). (Box 66)
    - Leather Brief album. (Box 66)
      - Komazawa Golf Link young Hirohito, Golf Club group photo, 1922
      - Matsudaira photo of young Empress.
      - Nippon Club women's group, March 29, 1928
      - * Prince and Princess Kaya, Banquet held by Japanese residents of New York, 1934; (approximately 12 × 20).
      - * Prince and Princess Takamatsu, Banquet held by Japanese comp(?), 1932
      - This is Japan Day photo during World War I in front of war memorial(?), October 9, 1918
      - * Japanese women in Red Cross uniforms in parade, (part of Japan Day?). Parade of Japanese Red Cross marching along 5th Ave., October 9, 1918 May 18, 1918.
      - Philadelphia Banquet honoring Mayor Hendrick and Ambassador Matsubaira, 1926
      - * Sayonara dinner tendered by Japan Economic Mission, in appreciation of friends in America, June 1937; 12 × 20.
      - * Seating List of above dinner at the Waldorf Astoria, June 15, 1937.
  - Photograph albums. (Box 67)
    - Meiji Government leadership portraits.
  - Photograph albums. (Box 68)
    - Individual portraits.
      - Teisaku Takagi, 1894 & 1886
      - YSB manager, Mrs. Takagi, 1886
      - Kaurokun Nakayama, 1882.
      - Dr. H.T. Yokura, 1882.
      - Baby photo, signed To Nidei & Otayasan From poor Mommie & Shikaya. Baby pictured lives about 3 yrs., Okamoto, 1888-91, 1889-1894.
- Diaries 1876-1910 (Box 70)
  - (folder 1 of 9), 1877 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - (folder 2 of 9), 1878 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - (folder 3 of 9), 1879 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - (folder 4 of 9), 1881 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - (folder 5 of 9), 1896 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - (folder 6 of 9), 1910 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - (folder 7 of 9) (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - (folder 8 of 9), 6 items (including 4 photos). (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - (folder 9 of 9), 16 items. (Box 70, Folder 9)
- Biographic Data I - Includes Yoneo Arai (Box 70)
  - Biographic materials., (folder 1 of 5) (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Personal., (folder 2 of 5) (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Biographic data., (folder 3 of 5) (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Financial records., (folder 4 of 5) (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - [cont.], (folder 5 of 5) (Box 70, Folder 14)
- Biographic Data II (Box 70, Box 71)
  - Richard Von Briessen., (folder 1-5 of 7) (Box 70, Folder 15-16, Folder 1-3)
  - Miscellaneous., (folder 6 of 7) (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - award to Ryichir, 1924; (folder 7 of 7) (Box 71, Folder 5)
- Ryichir's Letters in Tokyo to Brother (Box [71], Box [75])
  - ..., (folders 1-6 of 14) (Box 71, Folder 6-11)
  - ...., (1876); (folder 7 of 14) (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - ..., (folder 8-14 of 14) (Box 71, Folder 13-19)
  - 1 handkerchief. (Box 75, Folder 1)
- Copybooks - Ryichir on His Japan Trips (Box 71)
  - Copying books #5,6,7. (Box 71, Folder 20)
- Letters to Ryichir Arai from Friends, ca. 1900-10 (Box 71)
  - ...., [5 folders.] (Box 71, Folder 21-25)
- Ryichir Arai to Relatives & Friends after Arrival in New York, 1876 (Box 71)
  - ..., [3 folders.] (Box 71, Folder 26-28)
- Letters to Ryichir Arai from His Family (Box 71, Box 72)
  - ..., [9 folders.] (Box 71, Folder 29-34, Box 72)
- Letters of Ryichir Arai, 1876-81, re Satogumi Business Matters (Box 72)
  - ..., (folders 1-5 of 14) (Box 72, Folder 4-8)
  - B. Richardson. (folder 6 of 14), 1876 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - (folder 7 of 14). (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - ...., 1878; (folder 8 of 14) (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - ..., (folders 9-10 of 14) (Box 72, Folder 12-13)
  - ...., 1876-80; (folder 11 of 14) (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - (folders 12-14 of 14). (Box 72, Folder 15-17)
- Notes, Memoranda, Miscellaneous Mostly Undated (Box 72)
  - ..., (folder 1 of 2) (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous., (folder 2 of 2) (Box 72, Folder 19)
- Doshin Company Records (Box 72)
  - Proposals to Japanese Government re financial problems of the Doshin Company, 1890; (folder 1 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Briessen, 1885; (folder 2 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 21)
  - Petition to Japanese Government., (folder 3 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 22)
  - Draft proposal to continue direct silk trade, by Doshin Kaisha, March 1890; (folder 4 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Tokua trip., (folder 5 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Hoshino to Arai, re personal debts, 1900; (folder 6 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 25)
  - Silk Association of America - statistics of imports, 1891; (folder 7 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 26)
  - New York Silk Conditioning Works., (folder 8 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 27)
  - Financial records., (folder 9 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 28)
  - Agreement Doshin Co. & Yokohama Specie Bank, (Bank of Tokyo after World War I - now Union Bank), 1883; (folder 10 of 10) (Box 72, Folder 29)
- Yokohama Kiito Co. Financial Records & Papers (Box 72, Box 73)
  - Miscellaneous financial records & papers., (folder 1 of 5) (Box 72, Folder 30)
  - Financial papers & working papers., (folder 2 of 5) (Box 72, Folder 31)
  - Profit & loss statements., (folder 3 of 5) (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - ..., (folders 4-5 of 5) (Box 73, Folder 2-3)
- Yokohama Kiito Legal Papers (Box 73)
  - ...Drafts., (folder 1 of 4) (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Agreement, 1904; (folder 2 of 4) (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Yokohama Kiito - Gomei Kaisha agreement, September 20, 1900; (folder 3 of 4) (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Yokohama Kiito Kabushiki Kaisha: Lawyer's letters, 1915-18; (folder 4 of 4) (Box 73, Folder 7)
- Ryichir Arai's Letters re Job as Office Manager of Doshin Silk Trading Co. (Box 73)
  - Briessen., (folder 1 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - ..., (folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 9-10)
- Investment Company Reports (Box 73)
  - ..., [4 folders.] (Box 73, Folder 11-14)
- Original Letters (Box 73)
  - Ryichir Arai's original letters - in copybook. Unclear why Ryichir Arai retrieved them from Japan, (folder 1 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - ..., (folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 16-17)
- T. Scott Miyakawa re Arai Papers (Box 73)
  - Miyakawa - Arai letters re project. (Box 73, Folder 18)
- Unidentified (Box 73)
  - ..., [1 folder.] (Box 73, Folder 19)
- Envelopes (Box 73)
  - ..., [1 folder.] (Box 73, Folder 20)
- Bound Journals (Box 74)
  - Letters. (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - August 24, 1883-April 20, 1886. (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - January 3, 1888-December 11, 1890. (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - December 4, 1891-April 12, 1895. (Box 74, Folder 4)
- Ledger (Box 75)
  - No description given. In Middle Eastern language?, Bound. (Box 75, Folder 2)
- Morimura Brothers (Box 75)
  - Photographs. Portrait on left brother who came to U.S., 2 photographs mounted with leaf of text in Japanese. (Box 75, Folder 3)
- Ryichir Arai (Box 75)
  - Group and individual portraits., 3 items. (Box 75, Folder 4)
- Mr. and Mrs. Murai [Neighbors of Ryichir Arai] (Box 75)
  - Individual portraits., 2 items. (Box 75, Folder 5)